[Music]
the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet Museum of
hologography
[Music]
hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
and welcome to another week of holotalk
for the week of March 1st
1999 and happy march to you let's hope
spring gets here soon
this week we have a special broadcast
featuring holographic sound and we have
a few clips that you can download and
listen to also on the holotalk page and
in case you're one of those listeners
that Tunes out quickly I'd would like to
say to you that the clits sound best in
headphones so if you have headphones
that you can hook into your computer to
listen to the file all the better so
we're going to get back more on that and
the story of holographic sound in a few
minutes
I was in contact with Steve Michael and
I just want to make a report and pass a
report along to you from him that the
split beam hologram that he was
referring to in his last report was
actually a H1 H1 to H2 transfer so he
made a laser transmission hologram and
did the transfer onto a white light
reflection copy using his laser pointer
so that's very very exciting news
a few new items at hello world at the
website there's now a laser pointer
Forum where you can post questions or
have discussions on using laser pointers
to create holography I know this is a
very very new field almost a sub field
of holography it looks like it's turning
into and I thought it would be a good
idea for people to have an opportunity
to log on and share some of their ideas
some of their processing techniques what
works what doesn't and forum is a
wonderful way for individuals to get
together no matter what the distances
between us and exchange ideas and
comments suggest
cetera so we have a forum at the hollow
World site just look for the link and
it'll take you right there and if you
want to get into one of the discussions
just click on one of the discussions and
you can add a reply or if you have a
topic that you would like to start of
your own a brand new topic you can also
do that at the Forum as well
on the link page I have a new search
feature and what this search feature
does is it goes out and it sends a query
to all of the top search engines on the
internet and then it compiles your
results into one response now this is
according to keywords and if you hold
your mouse button down over the Box you
will see a long list of keywords that
you can send to the search engines for
your search the top keywords are for
holography and if you scroll down there
are also keywords that are more related
specifically to lasers so for lasers and
holography this is a wonderful feature
and it will allow you to get information
on the specific areas according to the
keywords that you're interested in and
all the keywords are cross reference to
lasers and holography for on-topic
results so try that out let me know how
that works for you
the Mensa 25th anniversary conference
excuse me that's coming up this Saturday
March 6th at the Holiday Inn Conference
Center in Tinton Falls New Jersey the
hotel is sold out there's no more room
at the Inn as they say
this is wonderful news I'm very excited
about going there and doing the keynote
presentation on Saturday night which
begins at 7 30 pm
and it is ten dollars if you want to get
just into the keynote address on
Saturday night I believe it's 35 or
maybe 50 if you want to attend the runs
for several days if you want to attend
several days but
if you have any questions send me an
email and if you're a whole talk
listener I'd love to meet you Saturday
night if you want to come out and we're
going to have some great Holograms there
the Holograms from Steve Michael will be
on display Holograms from John Claire
who was on holotalks not too many weeks
ago actually he's the person who goes
down into the caves and creates
Holograms and caves so you're going to
be able to see his cave Holograms there
as well Ronnie Anderson from Norway has
sent very very beautiful laser pointer
Holograms that he made and they're going
to be on display as well as as well as
my own Holograms that I've made here
that you've seen probably so many times
on the website when you're looking at
the laser pointer holography Pages you
can come out and see those Holograms
firsthand Saturday night March 6th 7 30
p.m at the Holiday Inn Conference Center
in Tinton Falls New Jersey it's very
easy to reach if you're on the North
South Expressway I don't have the exit
handy right here I'm sorry I think it
may be don't quote me on this I think it
may be Exit 115 and just as you go
through the toll booth
25 cents I believe
you go to the stoplight make a right and
Holiday Inn is right there so it's very
easy to reach in New Jersey New York
area
okay holographic sounds
many years ago maybe about 10 years or
more a friend of mine bought a tape over
by a man named zuccarelli from
zuccarelli holophonics Laboratories and
and showed A New Concept on
recording sound holographically and it
was very very impressive and now it's
also available on CD I will have a link
to that on the holotalk page where you
can go to the holophonics website and
I've contacted someone I sent an email
to holophonics to see if we could get
one of their
representatives on the holotalk show and
I just did that today because I didn't
even know they had a website I know
several weeks ago
I was looking for holophonics website
nothing came up so I think it may be a
brand new site
in any case what we're going to do is
we're going to talk a little bit about
holographic sound this week and you'll
have an opportunity to download several
of the samples and listen to them in
your headphones some incredible
experience and we're going to do that in
just a minute right after this message
would you like to make your own
one-of-a-kind hologram and learn how you
can start making holograms on your own
at the same time you can do this and
much more by attending one of Frankie's
greatest holography workshops from
beginner to Advanced Frank's got a
workshop that's just great for you from
single afternoon evening or weekend
introductory workshops to Wednesday
evening five-week complete courses and
don't forget his newest Workshop laser
pointer holography located just off the
Northeast Extension of the Pennsylvania
Turnpike and Interstate 78 the studio is
a quick non-stop drive from the New York
Philadelphia and Baltimore Washington DC
areas for more information call the
Studio's toll-free hotline at
1-800-458-3525 and begin your own
Journey with holography today that's
1-800-458-3525 for more information
telegraphy Workshop today
welcome back folks what I'm going to do
is I have printed out a few pages from
the holophonics website which explains
the process of holographic sound
and I'm going to read those to you
and what we're seeing here folks is
the possibility of someday having a
marriage of these two technologies
you've got holography which is a visual
medium
and now holographic sound which you can
listen to and the day will come when you
will be able to experience both of these
together for instance someone may be
holographically projected into your room
and when they speak instead of the sound
sounding like it's coming out of
speakers somewhere on the side of the
room or wherever you happen to have your
speakers placed
The Voice will actually emanate right
from the person's vocal cords inside
their body and as they move around the
room three-dimensionally because
there'll be a holographic figure The
Voice will travel with them and I've
listened to this disc there are quite a
few samples that are on this disc let's
see how many are on here actually 26 a
combination of sound clips and also
music
wonderful fireworks display I've chosen
two of them for you the matchbox shake
and the haircut hair dryer which are
short clips
and I've done this basically because of
the download time I had to use very high
quality compression in order to make
these files sound and work as good as
they should so I didn't want to have
anyone having an hour download time so I
picked two of the shortest samples that
are on the disk for you to experience
and there is a link to the holophonics
website if you'd like to go over and
experience a little bit more I think
they have a few Clips over there and
also the availability of ordering this
CD through the mail
and it's just an example that holography
really is
all around us we see holographic images
Holograms some of you have only
experienced holograms on your credit
cards and others have had the
opportunity of going to a gallery or a
museum and seeing larger display
Holograms and we sort of get into this
rut if you will that this is the only
thing about holography and that's not
true at all
the Holograms themselves are are very
simple physical manifestations of the
larger more encompassing universe as
hologram model
there are theories that the brain
functions holographically and also that
the universe itself is structured
holographically and the holographic
thought process
if you're able to think
in holographic terms brings you in tune
with the world and the universe
and as the season goes on we're going to
have additional shows that deal with
other aspects of holography as well
besides just holographic Imaging
so back to holographic sound
and I'm reading now
the holophonics technique is unique
because highest quality sound with full
spatial effect can be recorded without
the use of traditional microphones
the technology is based on a new
understanding of the physiology of human
hearing
and this new knowledge is utilized in
the recording process
holophonics is based on the hypothesis
that we do not perceive sound in a
passive manner
sound waves impacting our eardrums and
our brain Computing characteristics and
location from the frequency intensity
and arrival time at each ear
instead the technology is based on the
premise that the human ear generates its
own reference tone which interferes with
incoming sounds to create the necessary
spatial information for analysis by the
brain
it is the interference between external
sounds and the reference tone that
provides the brain with spatial
information
if external sounds are tape recorded
with synthesized reference sounds the
brain provides its own second reference
beam like laser beam shining through a
hologram it decodes reproducing the
original ambient conditions
consider the sphere of human oral
perception as being divided into
millions of minute points of awareness
and think of these points as all being
different color with each color relating
to a different position that the brain
could instantly identify
through reception of the colors
the Hue of sounds coming from behind the
listener would differ from the sounds
arriving in front
and the Brain can then perceive
Direction independent of intensity or
phase information
the holophonics technology replicates
this new definition of the hearing
process
holophonics recordings are based in the
interaction between the sound of reality
and the reference tone a listening
device has been developed which encodes
spatial information resulting from The
Encounter of the reference tone with
incoming sounds
these interference patterns represent
accurate spatial information as well as
the incoming sound itself
the listening device has been named and
its construction is based on the
understanding of the human hearing
system
it's actually named Ringo
to record Ringo is placed in the desired
position and connected to a standard
recording or broadcasting system
The Listener will hear the sounds which
reach Ringo from a 360 degree sphere
with accurate depth and spatial
information
again lingo does not contain traditional
microphones
instead the unique design and ability to
generate an appropriate reference tone
provides the basis for recording or
broadcasting the captured auditory
information
for The Listener this method of
recording does for the ears when
holographic pictures does for the eyes
it is three-dimensional reality Ringo
replaces microphones in the recording of
broadcast chains and can be connected to
any common recording or broadcasting
equipment with optimal results obtained
through digital technology
playback or broadcast as possible over
headphones or any existing mono or
stereo speaker system
with various levels of spatial effect
optimal effects occur when two tracks
stereo are played utilizing digital
technology over headphones
and minimal effect when played over a
single mono speaker
so there you have it folks I hope you
have a wonderful time
and I'm not going to come back on
actually the show will be over after I
say goodbye this time because there's
nothing coming on after me you'll have
to scroll down the page and download a
couple of the audio samples and listen
to them and I hope you have a wonderful
week
if you get a chance to come out to the
25th anniversary menta conference and
say hello and next week's show will
probably be the keynote address that I
give at the Mensa conference from
Saturday night but
if it turns out that I do not have
enough time to get that show together
I'm just going to leave this hollow talk
show up for an additional week and we
will follow that up the following week
with the keynote address at the Mensa
conference this is Frankie Freitas for
holotalk have a great week and see you
next week take care